We're back, everyone!
Welcome home!
Let me tell you about what
an absolutely perfect maid I was.
How was the entertainment district, Miss Erna?
Annette spent the whole time bullying me!
I want some warm milk!
Here you go.
I figured you might say that, so I made you some.
Ooh!
It really does feel lively,
now that we're all back together.
It's too loud in here.
I'm gonna head to my room.
Gotcha.
I'm not even close to done bragging yet!
Don't you want to hear how Maid Lily
took down Corpse's collaborator?
Y'know, technically you weren't
the one who took her down.
I mean, sure, but still...
Let her rest.
She pulled her weight in a big way,
and she's probably exhausted.
She was incredible, she really was.
She's a genius.
I can't even begin say how much
she saved our bacon.
Yeah, sure, I am a genius.
From your perspective, at least.
My eyes were opened up wide
By a scene that rent my heart
See it flitting, flitting through the gaps in your fingers
Stare at the truth as it comes into view
Is what's been built here paradise?
Tumbling down head over heels
Oh, I know this might be a wasteland
But I have to land so I can survive on my own
I have to go now
I vomited up magificent blood
That these flowers I planted here might bloom eternal
I love this hopeless world enough to give
All that my lungs and my legs and my hands have to give for it
And I swear I'll find a dream
That was worth all this sorrow
2 Months Ago ~ Darton, Galgad Empire Capital
As far as our preparations to infiltrate
the Endy Laboratory go,
FILE: Glint
the Intel squad, Operations squad,
and Specialist squad
are all giving it their all
to carry out their challenging tasks.
However, this is our first real mission,
and everyone is starting to slip up
and show signs of psychological strain.
Everyone, with one exception.
The success of the entire Impossible Mission
is resting on Monika's next operation,
and it's going to carry a fair bit of danger.
If necessary, I'm prepared to back her up myself.
Are you serious?
Yeah, I just got these bad boys in from Annette,
so I'll be fine all on my own.
Let Klaus know he can spend his time
helping the others.
Monika...
Why did they consider you
a washout at your academy?
If I told you it was 'cause I hit my ceiling...
would you believe me?
I'm kidding.
I just got bored and stopped trying, that's all.
Don't you worry about me.
If things look like they're going south,
I'll give up and get out of there.
C'mon, say something.
Hurry up already.
You've been getting a real big mouth lately.
'Specially considering your dad's
just a lowly electrician.
M-my dad's the best engineer in the whole Empire!
You think you can talk back to me?
You wanna get hit or something?
Wh-what was that?!
That hardly seems sporting.
I mean, three against one?
These next ones won't miss.
Guys, run!
E-excuse me, miss!
W-were those superpowers you just used?
Nah.
Then please, teach me how you did it!
I want to become strong like you.
That way, I can become a soldier
in the Imperial army someday!
A soldier?
Your objective is to extract information
from an engineer named Jordan Cupca.
He does a lot of electrical work
for the Endy Laboratory,
so he'll be well acquainted with the
lab's layout and inner workings.
His wife passed away,
so he lives alone with his young son Mattel.
Sure, why not.
I'll show you a thing or two once your school lets out.
Thank you!
Just so you know...
I can see you tailing me.
Who hired you?
Die!
I never made a single misstep.
Was Mattel the one he was following?
Is someone already keeping tabs on Jordan?
Well, if whoever it is is sending out
shitters like this guy,
then they're probably not an org worth worrying about.
At school, they taught me that being a soldier
is a good and noble job.
They said that before I was born,
the Imperial army bravely fought back the Allies
and defended our nation.
I want to become a strong soldier so I can protect
the Empire if there's ever another war.
That's my dream!
What's your dream, Coach?
Who, me?
I don't have one.
You don't?
Here's a question for you.
Let's say that you had a gift for playing soccer.
If you had the skills to be the best player in the world,
would you still want to be a soldier?
Or what if you could be the
biggest movie star in the world?
You'd have more money than
you knew what to do with,
women fawning over you,
and delicious food for every meal.
Would you give all that up to go live in
a cramped, musty set of barracks?
I don't know...
Or conversely,
what if you entered military school and ended up
at the absolute bottom of your class?
Would you still want to become a soldier then?
That does sound kind of unpleasant...
It's all just the scraps.
Us people,
we sort things into stuff that seems possible
and stuff that doesn't.
Then, we take the nicest thing we have left,
call it a dream, and cherish it.
Is that really how it works?
Say, I'm parched.
How about we stop at your place
and have something to drink?
Dang, sounds like this dad of yours is pretty great.
He is.
Someday, I want to help loads of people just like him!
I was born into a family of artists.
I'm so glad you were able to make it here safely.
On our side of the world,
there are no fires of war raging,
just the fires of artistic passion.
During the Great War, our whole family
evacuated to another continent.
I never actually saw its ravages for myself.
As far as artistic sensibilities went,
the well must have run dry after
my older brother and sister were born.
And what about your youngest?
I could take up instruments
and get praised for my playing,
and the paintings I drew got decent reviews, but...
Your art is technically competent,
but that's all it has going for it.
You're excellent at accurately copying things,
but your work has no heart.
I decide to walk the path of the spy
on little more than a hunch.
At the time, I thought that I'd made the right decision.
That I'd been born to work as a spy.
I was so sure of it.
Right up until that fateful day.
Wow! What a bunch of total weaklings!
I expected more out of you so-called top students.
You can go home now, rookie.
You should be proud of the fact that they let you
attend this special joint training exercise
just two months after you joined your academy.
You show promise.
The way you are now, though,
you aren't even close to good enough.
As it turned out, I was never one of the chosen ones.
Remember this.
In our world, people without fire in their hearts...
are nothing more than garbage.
That was the day I started half-assing my training.
Don't worry.
The drugs will wear off soon.
I'm back!
Don't turn around.
Hands up, slowly.
I took a look at your false-bottomed drawer.
That's quite the document you compiled.
Who are you?
Don't worry.
I'm on your side.
You want to defect, right?
I can help with that.
FILE: Glint
I've given up on the Empire.
That lab's been conducting human experiments
on death row convicts,
and they're still going on.
I decided to steal their secret data little by little.
That way, I could leak it to another country someday
and expose the Empire's misdeeds.
If you're investigating the lab,
then this is the best thing I could have asked for.
I would be more than happy to help.
There's too much here.
Didn't anyone get suspicious
while you were snatching up all this intel?
Mattel!
It's nice to meet you, Jordan Cupca.
We're here on behalf of Imperial counterintelligence.
You're under arrest for suspected espionage.
Th-there must be some sort of misunderstanding here.
I'm just a lowly electrician, and I've always
been completely faithful to the-
Dad!
Quit playing dumb, or you and the kid both get it!
Sorry, Jordan.
You were sloppy, and now, you're paying the price.
I swear,  I have no idea what you're talking about...
You know, I got the oddest report this morning.
Apparently, someone took out one of my agents.
You haven't made contact with
a foreign spy, have you?
I've already completed my mission.
There's no need to put myself in danger.
Answer me!
Dad!
Abandon the family.
As a spy, that's the correct call to make.
All I have to do is give up.
Just like I always have.
Look out, Teach, I've got a hostage!
If you come one step closer,
this report you wrote is going up in smoke!
And she's got me as her bodyguard, too.
How do ya like them apples?
Now you've got no choice but to surrender.
Magnificent.
I should just give up.
I'll never be like that examiner or like Teach.
No how much I work,
even if I spend my entire life trying,
I'll never be able to surpass them.
I'll just be a half-baked, slightly above-average spy
who gets used up and thrown away.
That's my lot in life.
What the hell is there to passionate about in that?
Bye.
Leave my dad alone!
You little shit!
Why?
Why am I still standing here?
Next time, we'll take Teach down for sure!
All these defeats have just been
paving the way to our victory!
Yeah! We can't keep losin' forever!
In that case, I have a plan I would like to try out.
I want to be part of the attack team next time.
I-if it's all right, I have an idea I'd like to share!
I want to play with Klaus too, yo!
Next time, my honey trap will take him down for sure.
Well, this feels like shit.
Do it!
Stand up!
Fight back!
Are they starting to rub off on me?
That's hilarious.
Dad...
Don't you care what happens to
your adorable little son?
Out with it already!
Who's there?
Plunging the room into darkness was a bad move.
I can sense everything that happens in here
through my fingertips.
And you couldn't have warned me about that first?
Coach?
Don't play with your food.
End it.
I know, I know.
You're no fun.
Got you.
What a shame.
You weren't up to par.
That technique hardly seems fair.
Feeling confident enough to make small talk, are we?
Coach!
It's so handy, I'm gonna have to use it against you.
I can feel it, too.
My captured arm is telling me the
position of every single wire.
What?
Damn you, child!
She's just throwing them blind!
She won't keep getting lucky shots in!
Oh, please.
Why aren't they getting caught by my wire net?
It's just math.
What?!
I've got a knack for calculations.
Now that I know where your wires are,
all I have to do is make sure
my rebounds weave between them.
That's impossible!
Nobody could do that!
Couldn't they?
I'm code name Glint,
now, let's harbor love for as long as we can.
Kill the hostages!
What do you think you're doing?
I could ask you the same thing...
Back when you beat Lily and Sybilla,
you probably did it
by having them catch each other in friendly fire.
Isn't that right, Klaus?
Dad!
Mattel...
Looks like neither of you got hurt.
Wh-who in the world are you?
Like I told you, someone who's on your side.
Go to this address and give them this password.
They'll give you asylum in the Republic.
From the bottom of my heart, thank you.
You've done so much for us.
Are you sure you're all right, though?
Don't you worry about me.
When you said you didn't have superpowers,
you never told me you knew magic, Coach!
That wasn't magic.
I can run calculations a bit faster
than most people, that's all.
Creepshot...
That's the only ability I have.
Pretty underwhelming, right?
Not at all!
You're the best spy in the whole world, Coach!
I want to become strong like you!
You really are in league of your own, Monika.
The boss was right
when he said it was a stroke of good luck
finding you amongst the academy washouts.
He described your talents as
"frighteningly magnificently."
Oh yeah?
Who knew our Klaus was such a flatterer.
Would you mind if I asked you another question?
Two days ago, you told me that you stopped trying
because you hit your ceiling.
That was why you washed out at your academy.
Oh yeah? Did I?
If that's the case, why do you choose
to stay in Lamplight?
I don't have any big fancy reason,
but if I had to pick one...
Yes?
I guess it'd be the friendly faces.
I think that's a wonderful answer.
The Present
What happened?
I was so sure that now that we'd
completed our big missions,
we would be strong enough to overpower Teach...
We fucked up and used way too much gunpowder.
How unlucky...
This team would be in a sorry state without me.
A sorry state indeed.
Look, I've got a plan that might be worth trying.
I'm in!
Another year, another test that nobody passed.
Same deal with the boys.
That makes, what, ten years running?
I don't know why we even keep doing this.
Running this Inferno recruitment exam
disguised as a special training exercise, that is.
The way I see it,
the problem is how we set the passing condition
as having skills on par with Klaus's or better.
That girl showed promise, but she wasn't up to snuff.
It doesn't matter how exceptional
someone's talents are,
they'll never make the grade
with a heart as frozen over as hers.
True.
But the thing about people is, they change.
And that transformation...
can be magnificent.